CURRICULUM VITAE

Komal Shankar Rao

Career Objective:

Secure a responsible and challenging position in a reputable organization to expand my learnings, knowledge, and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company. I would like to associate myself with an organization that provides me with the opportunity to use my variety of skills and experience to contribute in a meaningful way to the advancement of the company goals. Ability to maintain strong working relationships and build credibility with various employment levels within the organization.

Educational Qualification:

- B.Com Sri Mahaveer Jain College, Bangalore (2010)
- P.U.C Sri Mahaveer Jain College, Bangalore (2007)
- SSLC The Kenmore School, Bangalore (2005)

Skills:

- > Good Communication and interpersonal skills
- > Excellent problem solving skills
- > Strong analytical skills.
- > Knowledge of 7 QC tools.
- > A creative mindset and ability to approach a problem creatively.
- > Training skills.
- > Time management skills, the ability to prioritize, organise and schedule work.
- > Strong sales skills.
- > Customer service.
- > Well-versed with MS Excel, word, and power points

Experience:

1) Unacademy - Worked as Senior Quality analyst and Training From 2019 - 2022.

- Handling a team of 15-20 agents to assess the quality of performance.
- Conducting call quality audit and sampling for the daily calls made (Inbound and outbound)
- Identify the gaps and provide constructive feedback.
- Reviewing monthly with each team member of their individual quality scores, having them listen or evaluate the calls themselves.
- Create and publish detailed reports on the department quality audit score, frequently missed standards and recommendations for areas of improvement.
- Drive process improvement initiatives and training for the team for achieving call quality metrics.
- Drive call calibration sessions, refresher sessions with agents to improve call quality.
- Prepare TNI and train the agents accordingly.
- Conducting quality induction for new hire batch.
- Working closely with the team manager to drive high collection activities such as, identifying opportunities to increase collections and conduct regular and close discussions with the team managers.
- Provide a monthly overview report to the Director, Assistant Director and managers.
- Conducting regular PKT's to understand agents process knowledge.
- Identifying the areas require for training, collaborating with the training team to build modules and ensure gaps are filled with defined TAT.
- Plan and improve training workshops and projects to monitor and groom poor performers and bottom quartile, Working on RCA.

2) Azuga telematics private limited - Worked as Lead Generation Specialist From 2018 - 2019

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Qualify and establish contact with companies and take prospects from initial contact phase to qualified phase over the phone.
- Targeting and engaging leads by creating lead generation funnels based on different tech and business domains.
- Prospect new customers through email campaign and cold calling.
- Create new sales opportunities by identifying and reaching out to the correct decision makers through cold calls and emails.
- Use proven methodologies of ABM to generate qualified leads according to the business targets.
- Maintain a dashboard and prepare weekly reports and communicate the progress.
- Schedule demonstrations and presentations with the decision maker.

3) Accenture - Worked as Customer Service Associate From 2017 - 2018

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Managing and resolving customer queries and routine problems.
- Handling escalations and complaints of dissatisfied customers & giving best resolutions.
- Responsible for closing the faults and complaints with in the SLA's.
- Individual contributor as a part of a team, with a predetermined, focused scope of

work.

4) Alain Services - Worked as **Business Development Executive** from August 2014 to September 2017.

Rolls and Responsibilities:

- Connecting with US based students who's looking to complete education via distance learning.
- Establishing contact and introducing the uniqueness and effectiveness of online /blended learning.
- Being a mentor and counselling potential students to achieve their educational path and understanding how can we catalyse their learning.
- Carrying weekly enrolment / revenue and collection target.
- Owning the complete sales closing life cycle for leads assigned. This includes making phone calls, product demonstration, salesclosing, and post-sales relationship management.
- Maintaining a detailed database of all the interactions on the CRM with the leads and providing constant feedback to the marketing team on lead quality.

Personal Profile:

Name: Komal Shankar Rao

Address: # 9/1 OVH Road, Basavangudi, Bangalore – 560004.

Karnataka, INDIA.

Marital Status: Single

Nationality: Indian

Gender: Female

Language Known: English, Hindi, Kannada & Marathi

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I believe my qualifications and skills are compatible with your requirements. I request an opportunity to deliver, perform and prove.